leonardo muñoz

Front-End Engineer



I'm a JS lover from Mexico City with 6+ years of experience specializing in front-end technologies. I build web apps with a focus on smooth UX that users can enjoy. I put special care in writing nice and clean code that is easy to maintain.

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Developer

Grio Mexico | Jul 2019 - Today

- Develop a browser-based responsive web app using React and Material UI.
- Build a library of reusable React components implementing Redux as state manager.
- Reduce app's loading time by virtualizing render of large data sets.
- Boosted app's performance by inspecting code's impact on React's lifecycle..
- Set and evaluate periodic goals alongside with stakeholders.
- Reduce app's loading time by virtualizing render of large data sets.

Angular Developer

Globant Mexico / Sourceability | Oct 2018 - Jul 2019

- Improved user experience by redesigning widgets to be interactive and facilitate the user to manipulate data and rearrange layouts.
- Reduced app's initial loading time by better bootstrapping Angular and better managing DOM manipulation.
- · Followed Scrum methodology.

Javascript Developer

Globant Mexico / Zaplabs | Sept 2017 - Oct 2018

- Developed web tools to consolidate the administration of the brand's subsidiaries' blogs under a single site.
- Developed new features for blogs using plain Javascript and ES6.
- · Followed Kanban methodology.

React developer

Globant Mexico / DWA Nova | Sept 2016 - Aug 2017

- Developed a cross-platform desktop app for managing Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator assets using frontend technologies.
- Created desktop app with React + Redux and Electron, and Adobe plugin with HTML/Javascript.
- Integrated with Node server for local file storage through sockets with WebSockets and socket.io.
- Unit tests done with Mocha, Chai, Sinon and Enzyme.

AngularJS Developer

Globant Mexico / United Airlines | Nov 2015 - Sept 2016

- Developed a control panel to administrate personnel and daily tasks using AngularJS, ES6 and SASS.
- Created widgets with a focus on reusability to share components among projects.
- Automated tasks to build environment and scaffold components using Webpack and Gulp scripts.
- Followed Scrum methodology.

.NET Developer

Indigo Smart Software Development | Aug 2015 - Nov 2015

- Designed and created an API for processing payments in an e-commerce application using .NET.
- Maintenance of existing RESTful web services of a flight ticket booking application.

Instructor KMMX | 2014 - 2015

• Taught courses about HTML5 APIs and features, AJAX with PHP and Java Fundamentals to students ranging from beginners to IT specialists.

EDUCATION

Diplomate Course Embedded Linux

University of Mexico (UNAM)

B.S. in Electrical & Electronics Engineering

University of Mexico (UNAM)

SKILLS

Technical

JS (ES2020)

React

Redux

NodeJS

Jest

Webpack

npm

Git

Scripting

Scrum methodology

Responsive design

Database programming

REST